all right ready to set record we're
going to talk about the any type
otherwise known as the untyped interface
and how to avoid looking like a noob
since go 1.19 the any type has taken
place of the in of the of the the
untyped interface what do I mean so if
you want to type and you want to pass a
thing to something you can say VAR it
isn't any and you can assign literally
anything to it you can type you can type
something right
you can type it equals one let's see if
that dies shall
we go run temp f.
go and it's like uhoh can't do it right
I think we probably have to pick one I
think the type is defined on his first
assignment um no new variables on left
side of blah all right it we have to
print it let's print it fmt print l
in I I'm a little
drunk so
here we go go run there what the
hell oh whoopsie I I did a thing up
there you guys know about I I suck a go
I'm horrible why are you watching this
okay so I'm sure I'm going to get
comments um something okay so it printed
something right let's see if this
actually
works nope why can't we do that because
it was assigned a string type the first
time what we can do is this though we
can say I now I want it to be one
right now we're going to print it and
it'll print a
one and you guys know about print app
right this is super cool check this out
this is you probably know print app from
other languages about the T the T will
print its type it'll print its type you
go run they say it's an INT well we
forgot our line return all right we'll
put line return here all right
fine all right go in
what happens if I change it I do this I
use this one
instead what's going to do going BL what
does that have to do with being an any
well neither of those are any right but
if I do bar it
any and and I and I assign it like
this you I want you to see the
difference so now it says it's a string
right and we're going to change this one
to one
say I want this to be a thing and it
changes the type dynamically it changes
the type depending on what's assigned to
it it can hold any type and there's a
million other ways to do this um however
this is actually the same as this big
long ass thing that we used to have to
type we don't have to type that anymore
thank God they added generics and also
the any type and in doing so have like
saved us all and what I want to show you
is that you can actually look up this
type and you can can see that the type
any is simply an
alias for an untyped interface or they
what they call the I'm sorry the empty
interface just to be I m I misspoke it's
the empty interface so the empty
interface is the any type and it is
unique to go and it is absolutely an
amazing thing um you know I'm not going
to teach you the whole thing now go
learn about it you'll learn about it a
lot I am going to put together series
about how to learn to program Ino as
your first language um I've decided but
if you just want a chance to T to play
around with this play around with the
anti type the anti type is really good
this is not generics by the way if you
know what generics are it's a totally
different Beast uh that was added in
1.19 ago as well so hopefully that'll
give you a little bit of a sense of what
any is